<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://shikon.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://shikon.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-01-08T18:34:06-05:00</updated><id>https://shikon.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Shiko</title><subtitle>Just a random asian's project</subtitle><author><name>Lan Hu</name></author><entry><title type="html">Designing a Nixie HV supply part 1</title><link href="https://shikon.github.io/electronics/a-pcb-design/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Designing a Nixie HV supply part 1" /><published>2021-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-01-07T14:00:23-05:00</updated><id>https://shikon.github.io/electronics/a-pcb-design</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shikon.github.io/electronics/a-pcb-design/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;backstory&quot;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well basically the backstory is the introduction but shht :). Recently I designed a small PCB with an analog switch for my internship project. This made me remember, I still have to finish my PCB I was doing for my nixie tube clock. Don’t know what those are? Well, here is an example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shikon/cloudimg/master/typora/xclock_small.jpg.pagespeed.ic.5qBb-pWZkY.webp&quot; alt=&quot;Meinbergnews&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I noticed that a huge area was taken by the high-voltage (HV) supply. It is a NCH6100HV, which I bought a couple years ago… The voltage is changeable by a potentiometer, great to experiment with. I was motivated to make it smaller but not only that. During the previous design process, I noticed creating your supplies is something any electronics project is needed. In my case I couldn’t use the very efficient switch-mode power supplies (SMPS) on my small analog switch PCB, as these typically have a lot of switching noise. They would be ideal as you can easily go up in voltage (boost) or down (buck). This made me intrigued but I couldn’t spend time to explore this. Well, during my New years break however, that means project time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;interwebs-a-gold-mine&quot;&gt;Interwebs, a gold mine&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember few years ago reading about these supplies being made by hobbyist. So I re-googled these projects and they became a great resource for my nixie tube HV supply. I mainly used these resources:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://desmith.net/NMdS/Electronics/NixiePSU.html&quot;&gt;de Smith&lt;/a&gt; focusses mainly on layout&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jan.rychter.com/high-voltage-power-supply-for-nixie-tube-projects&quot;&gt;Jan Rychter&lt;/a&gt; focusses on general design specifications&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://0x7d.com/2017/nixie-tube-clock/#Custom_Power_Supply&quot;&gt;0x7d&lt;/a&gt; includes some general information about a few working principles of SMPS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having scanned over these great projects it was time to dive into the theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;working-principle-of-smps&quot;&gt;Working principle of SMPS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal is to create a DC high-voltage supply from a lower voltage supply.  Just like climbing a mountain going up is a bit more difficult than going down. An example, a bad one however, is to create a lower voltage is using a so called voltage divider. If the load isn’t too heavy its fine but due to the fixed output impedance of the resistive ladder it will be easily disturbed by its load.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shikon/cloudimg/master/typora/330px-Impedance_voltage_divider.svg.png&quot; alt=&quot;Wikipedia&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;tes asdjkhdaskajsdhfa hjksda sjkhdahks dakhjst&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lan Hu</name></author><category term="electronics" /><category term="PCB" /><category term="CAD" /><category term="design" /><category term="project" /><summary type="html">Backstory Well basically the backstory is the introduction but shht :). Recently I designed a small PCB with an analog switch for my internship project. This made me remember, I still have to finish my PCB I was doing for my nixie tube clock. Don’t know what those are? Well, here is an example: I noticed that a huge area was taken by the high-voltage (HV) supply. It is a NCH6100HV, which I bought a couple years ago… The voltage is changeable by a potentiometer, great to experiment with. I was motivated to make it smaller but not only that. During the previous design process, I noticed creating your supplies is something any electronics project is needed. In my case I couldn’t use the very efficient switch-mode power supplies (SMPS) on my small analog switch PCB, as these typically have a lot of switching noise. They would be ideal as you can easily go up in voltage (boost) or down (buck). This made me intrigued but I couldn’t spend time to explore this. Well, during my New years break however, that means project time! Interwebs, a gold mine I remember few years ago reading about these supplies being made by hobbyist. So I re-googled these projects and they became a great resource for my nixie tube HV supply. I mainly used these resources: de Smith focusses mainly on layout Jan Rychter focusses on general design specifications 0x7d includes some general information about a few working principles of SMPS Having scanned over these great projects it was time to dive into the theory. Working principle of SMPS The goal is to create a DC high-voltage supply from a lower voltage supply. Just like climbing a mountain going up is a bit more difficult than going down. An example, a bad one however, is to create a lower voltage is using a so called voltage divider. If the load isn’t too heavy its fine but due to the fixed output impedance of the resistive ladder it will be easily disturbed by its load. tes asdjkhdaskajsdhfa hjksda sjkhdahks dakhjst</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Drawing O-rings for dad aka printing O-rings for dad part 2</title><link href="https://shikon.github.io/3d-printing/drawing-orings/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Drawing O-rings for dad aka printing O-rings for dad part 2" /><published>2020-12-28T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-12-28T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://shikon.github.io/3d-printing/drawing-orings</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shikon.github.io/3d-printing/drawing-orings/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;practicalities&quot;&gt;Practicalities…&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While waiting for my Sainsmart 3D TPU filament to arrive, I still needed some other parts before I could start the printing. That is a CAD drawing of such O-ring. I thought I would finish this in a couple of minutes, I mean how hard could it be? I simply draw a ring and that’s it. Always, in practice or in reality if you want, it does not come easy. At least if you are unexperienced, things you know how to, well… you know how to. Therefore they are easy :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;o-ring-or-square-ring&quot;&gt;O-ring or square-ring?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First I started with two circles, and then you would extrude it up a little to get a 3D part. Circles are 2D as they “live” in a plane. If you could pull it up well then you would end up with a sort of squished cylinder and it becomes 3D! Something like below. But then I realized in my situation I would prefer not to have 2 “flat” sides. Which ends up to be more of a square ring. &lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shikon/cloudimg/master/typora/Fusion360_vJH1eaxSPz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fusion360_vJH1eaxSPz&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To mimic a real O-ring both sides would’ve have been well round and like a circle, but this is unpractical for a 3D-printer. Since it prints on a flat surface, one side eventually ends up flat. Therefore, it would be stupid to draw it round. Well you could try, but that would mean the following printed layers have to “fly”. This is called overhang and while it allows for some I might as well just draw it flat as in my use case it would be perfectly fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous method was not what I wanted exactly, as I end up with 2 flat surfaces, well my next method was to draw a circle and cut it in half, let this rotate over an axis that such far away it is equal to the inner radius I want ~4.5cm. So I start of drawing a circle in the origin…. This was a bad plan. Somehow I could not move it, well because fusion fixes/constraints it to the origin. After some googling I found this out, and it was suggested to remove this constraint, however trying to do this didn’t help. I gave up and just drew another circle but not taking the origin at the center of the circle. I ended up with something that looked quite decent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shikon/cloudimg/master/typora/OppIvZA.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh I also added some fillets, what are those? Well those nice roundings, at the left and right corner. Ah remember what I said about not being able to print flying things? Yeah maybe the overhang angle is a bit too aggressive. Also maybe I want it to be a bit thicker, lets add a square to the bottom. Here we go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shikon/cloudimg/master/typora/9WNW648.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we move it away from the origin ~4.5 cm and revolve and we end up with something that is looking promising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shikon/cloudimg/master/typora/vdM7ENO.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-now&quot;&gt;What now?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well I exported the file as a STL, next I will set the Cura profile and slice it and test both “O-ring” designs. The one with fillets and one with a square. Also I designed the width of the O-ring to be 5 mm, from the CAD program it seems to be a bit too wide. I just randomly chose this as it seemed to be quite okay. But I might redesign it for 4 mm, or smaller. As I am a real fusion360 noob, I do not know how to make it parametric. That means I tell the program, that the things I draw can be varied, and just changing this number somewhere in the program which I do not know yet. I can easily adjust various dimensions of the object. Some important parameters here would be: inner diameter, width and height. That is the next thing to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;ps&quot;&gt;PS&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh since probably nobody reads this blog yet, I am not going to bother yet/I do not know how I am going to implement this. But these files can be made available, for now just shoot me a mail!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lan Hu</name></author><category term="3D-printing" /><category term="first time" /><category term="fusion360" /><category term="CAD tool" /><summary type="html">Practicalities… While waiting for my Sainsmart 3D TPU filament to arrive, I still needed some other parts before I could start the printing. That is a CAD drawing of such O-ring. I thought I would finish this in a couple of minutes, I mean how hard could it be? I simply draw a ring and that’s it. Always, in practice or in reality if you want, it does not come easy. At least if you are unexperienced, things you know how to, well… you know how to. Therefore they are easy :). O-ring or square-ring? First I started with two circles, and then you would extrude it up a little to get a 3D part. Circles are 2D as they “live” in a plane. If you could pull it up well then you would end up with a sort of squished cylinder and it becomes 3D! Something like below. But then I realized in my situation I would prefer not to have 2 “flat” sides. Which ends up to be more of a square ring. To mimic a real O-ring both sides would’ve have been well round and like a circle, but this is unpractical for a 3D-printer. Since it prints on a flat surface, one side eventually ends up flat. Therefore, it would be stupid to draw it round. Well you could try, but that would mean the following printed layers have to “fly”. This is called overhang and while it allows for some I might as well just draw it flat as in my use case it would be perfectly fine. The previous method was not what I wanted exactly, as I end up with 2 flat surfaces, well my next method was to draw a circle and cut it in half, let this rotate over an axis that such far away it is equal to the inner radius I want ~4.5cm. So I start of drawing a circle in the origin…. This was a bad plan. Somehow I could not move it, well because fusion fixes/constraints it to the origin. After some googling I found this out, and it was suggested to remove this constraint, however trying to do this didn’t help. I gave up and just drew another circle but not taking the origin at the center of the circle. I ended up with something that looked quite decent. Oh I also added some fillets, what are those? Well those nice roundings, at the left and right corner. Ah remember what I said about not being able to print flying things? Yeah maybe the overhang angle is a bit too aggressive. Also maybe I want it to be a bit thicker, lets add a square to the bottom. Here we go. Now we move it away from the origin ~4.5 cm and revolve and we end up with something that is looking promising. What now? Well I exported the file as a STL, next I will set the Cura profile and slice it and test both “O-ring” designs. The one with fillets and one with a square. Also I designed the width of the O-ring to be 5 mm, from the CAD program it seems to be a bit too wide. I just randomly chose this as it seemed to be quite okay. But I might redesign it for 4 mm, or smaller. As I am a real fusion360 noob, I do not know how to make it parametric. That means I tell the program, that the things I draw can be varied, and just changing this number somewhere in the program which I do not know yet. I can easily adjust various dimensions of the object. Some important parameters here would be: inner diameter, width and height. That is the next thing to learn. PS Oh since probably nobody reads this blog yet, I am not going to bother yet/I do not know how I am going to implement this. But these files can be made available, for now just shoot me a mail!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello world!</title><link href="https://shikon.github.io/first%20steps/hello-world/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello world!" /><published>2020-12-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-12-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://shikon.github.io/first%20steps/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shikon.github.io/first%20steps/hello-world/">&lt;p&gt;The quick brown fox jumped over  the lazy dog…
This is my first test post.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lan Hu</name></author><category term="First steps" /><category term="Hello world!" /><category term="first time" /><category term="standard" /><summary type="html">The quick brown fox jumped over the lazy dog… This is my first test post.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Printing O-rings for dad</title><link href="https://shikon.github.io/3d-printing/printing-orings/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Printing O-rings for dad" /><published>2020-12-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-12-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>https://shikon.github.io/3d-printing/printing-orings</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://shikon.github.io/3d-printing/printing-orings/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;backstory&quot;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today dad asked me if I could buy an O-ring as he needed one. The situation is as follows, the water drainage has a cup (diameter 9 cm) which seals the sewer air from the environment. It broke so it started to smell, and we all know the sewers are nasty…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple months ago I bought myself a Creality ender 5 3D-printer. Mainly to support my maker hobbies, but maybe covid-19 accelerated this quite expensive purchase. I recently had some severe stringing issues using the stock hot end, therefore I upgraded to a direct-drive setup. Due to lower retraction settings, the stringing issues were solved. One of the main advantages of this upgrade is being able to print flexible filaments. Although, not my main reason, this was the perfect excuse for myself to buy some flexible filament. Since my dad wanted to replace 2 and have a few backup, I suggested to print them using my 3D-printer.  Googling a O-ring of 9 cm diameter, the costs were about ~€2,50- a piece, requiring 6 of them totaled ~ €20,- including shipping. I realized it should be easy to print an O-ring for much less. It was time for some more in-depth research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-internet-theory&quot;&gt;The internet (theory)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a huge fan of the internet, you type in a few keywords in google and you get loads of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the search started with googling &lt;em&gt;TPU filament&lt;/em&gt;, and the first hit was a post from www.all3dp.com, which I quite like. Their posts are quite neat, comprehensive and a overall good read. I read a small part about TPE’s which TPU is a subclass of TPE. Due to the huge popularity and success of TPU, TPE faded into the background, hence I didn’t concern me over these materials anymore.  Now I needed to check a few things whether it was possible to print it with my machine. Mainly I was concerned about the printing temperatures and adhesion. I needed the following requirements,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;requirements&quot;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nozzle temperature: &amp;lt;285 °C (limited by hot end)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Warping: Minimal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shrinkage: Minimal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flexibility: Very high&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cura profile&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amazon available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to have a successful print the material should show low warping and shrinkage, this makes it easier and more fault-tolerant. Flexibility speaks for itself here… And to accelerate the time for product a pre-configured Cura profile by the manufacturer or other makers is highly preferred. Lastly, if possible I should be able to buy it from Amazon, as the shipping with prime is free and saves me money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tpu-brands&quot;&gt;TPU brands&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I have learnt the hard way is to never go for the cheapest filament. I would not say the cheaper filaments are bad, but you pay in your time of setting it up and calibrating it. Hence my preference for an available print profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The article discussed the following series of TPU’s,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;MatterHackers Pro&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NinjaTek NinjaFlex&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NinjaTek Cheetah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NinjaTek Armadillo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fillamentum Flexfill&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PolyFlex&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SainSmart&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All with varying properties, the main important parameter for me here was the hardness. All of them were such that they are decent flexible filaments, this can be seen by the &lt;strong&gt;elongation at break&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shikon/cloudimg/master/typora/varioshore.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;varioshore&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another interesting filament was &lt;strong&gt;colorFabb’s varioshore&lt;/strong&gt;. By changing the print settings one could tune the flexibility of this material. Its principle of working is, there is an additive in the filament which expands as a gas and introduces bubbles into the material. High school chemistry tells that the hotter one warms up a substance the larger its volume. Using the Ideal gas law, 
\(\mathrm{PV}=n\mathrm{RT}\)
with P the pressure, V the volume, n the amount of substance, R the gas constant and T the temperature. These pore (gas bubbles) sizes determine then the flexibility of the final print.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although very interesting it brings in many parameters to be tuned and would only complicate the design of this simple element. And therefore require more time. It is not too expensive for  ~€50,- a 800g spool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;amazon&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well looking at amazon.de, I didn’t get much to choose from. A quick search only gave a few smaller brands and &lt;em&gt;SainSmart&lt;/em&gt; all3dp was quite positive of this filament. Looking up this filament I found that they had a Ender 3 Cura profile, considering the similarity between Ender 3 and 5 I knew I could take this profile and just use it with little tweaking and I was SOLD. It was cheap too and orange :).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/shikon/cloudimg/master/typora/firefox_WbcL291AXV.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-now&quot;&gt;What now?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well I will design a very simple ring in Autodesk Fusion360 and hopefully swapping out the filament will be easy. I might wait for my backup nozzles and separate my nozzles to  their material type. So nozzles X only for PLA, nozzle Y for PETG and nozzle Z for TPU. To be continued….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h1&gt;</content><author><name>Lan Hu</name></author><category term="3D-printing" /><category term="first time" /><category term="standard" /><summary type="html">Backstory Today dad asked me if I could buy an O-ring as he needed one. The situation is as follows, the water drainage has a cup (diameter 9 cm) which seals the sewer air from the environment. It broke so it started to smell, and we all know the sewers are nasty… A couple months ago I bought myself a Creality ender 5 3D-printer. Mainly to support my maker hobbies, but maybe covid-19 accelerated this quite expensive purchase. I recently had some severe stringing issues using the stock hot end, therefore I upgraded to a direct-drive setup. Due to lower retraction settings, the stringing issues were solved. One of the main advantages of this upgrade is being able to print flexible filaments. Although, not my main reason, this was the perfect excuse for myself to buy some flexible filament. Since my dad wanted to replace 2 and have a few backup, I suggested to print them using my 3D-printer. Googling a O-ring of 9 cm diameter, the costs were about ~€2,50- a piece, requiring 6 of them totaled ~ €20,- including shipping. I realized it should be easy to print an O-ring for much less. It was time for some more in-depth research. The internet (theory) I am a huge fan of the internet, you type in a few keywords in google and you get loads of information. So the search started with googling TPU filament, and the first hit was a post from www.all3dp.com, which I quite like. Their posts are quite neat, comprehensive and a overall good read. I read a small part about TPE’s which TPU is a subclass of TPE. Due to the huge popularity and success of TPU, TPE faded into the background, hence I didn’t concern me over these materials anymore. Now I needed to check a few things whether it was possible to print it with my machine. Mainly I was concerned about the printing temperatures and adhesion. I needed the following requirements, Requirements Nozzle temperature: &amp;lt;285 °C (limited by hot end) Warping: Minimal Shrinkage: Minimal Flexibility: Very high Cura profile Amazon available In order to have a successful print the material should show low warping and shrinkage, this makes it easier and more fault-tolerant. Flexibility speaks for itself here… And to accelerate the time for product a pre-configured Cura profile by the manufacturer or other makers is highly preferred. Lastly, if possible I should be able to buy it from Amazon, as the shipping with prime is free and saves me money. TPU brands One of the things I have learnt the hard way is to never go for the cheapest filament. I would not say the cheaper filaments are bad, but you pay in your time of setting it up and calibrating it. Hence my preference for an available print profile. The article discussed the following series of TPU’s, MatterHackers Pro NinjaTek NinjaFlex NinjaTek Cheetah NinjaTek Armadillo Fillamentum Flexfill PolyFlex SainSmart All with varying properties, the main important parameter for me here was the hardness. All of them were such that they are decent flexible filaments, this can be seen by the elongation at break. Another interesting filament was colorFabb’s varioshore. By changing the print settings one could tune the flexibility of this material. Its principle of working is, there is an additive in the filament which expands as a gas and introduces bubbles into the material. High school chemistry tells that the hotter one warms up a substance the larger its volume. Using the Ideal gas law, \(\mathrm{PV}=n\mathrm{RT}\) with P the pressure, V the volume, n the amount of substance, R the gas constant and T the temperature. These pore (gas bubbles) sizes determine then the flexibility of the final print. Although very interesting it brings in many parameters to be tuned and would only complicate the design of this simple element. And therefore require more time. It is not too expensive for ~€50,- a 800g spool. Amazon Well looking at amazon.de, I didn’t get much to choose from. A quick search only gave a few smaller brands and SainSmart all3dp was quite positive of this filament. Looking up this filament I found that they had a Ender 3 Cura profile, considering the similarity between Ender 3 and 5 I knew I could take this profile and just use it with little tweaking and I was SOLD. It was cheap too and orange :). What now? Well I will design a very simple ring in Autodesk Fusion360 and hopefully swapping out the filament will be easy. I might wait for my backup nozzles and separate my nozzles to their material type. So nozzles X only for PLA, nozzle Y for PETG and nozzle Z for TPU. To be continued…. Resources</summary></entry></feed>